<resources>
    <string name="app_name">SkinSprite</string>
    <string name="welcome">Welcome to SkinSprite\nUnlock Radiant Skin with SkinSprite</string>
    <string name="Login">Login</string>
    <string name="SignUp">Sign Up</string>
    <string name="UserName">UserName</string>
    <string name="Password">Password</string>
    <string name="btn_1">check your problem</string>
    <string name="btn_2">scan/view your prescriptions</string>
    <string name="btn_3">meds notifier</string>
    <string name="btn_4">settings</string>
    <string name="btn_5">order meds online </string>
    <string name="btn_6">your account history</string>
    <string name="HealthTip">Skin health Tip</string>
    <string name="MailId">abc@example.com</string>
    <string name="Tip"> Promote hand hygiene and basic sanitation practices to prevent skin infections. Access to clean water and basic hygiene facilities is crucial.</string>
    <string name="RememberMe">Remember Me</string>
    <string name="RecyclerView_Heading">Order Medicines Online </string>
    <string name="Option_1mg">Order medicine using  1mg </string>
    <string name="Option_PharmEasy">Order medicine using PharmEasy</string>
    <string name="Option_Netmeds">Order medicine using Netmeds</string>
    <string name="Option_Medlife">Order medicine using Medlife</string>
    <string name="Option_Practo">Order medicine using Practo</string>
    <string name="Option_Amazon_Pharmacy">Order medicine using Amazon Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="Option_Apollo_To_Name_A_Few">Order medicine using Apollo</string>
    <string name="Option_1mg_url">https://www.1mg.com/</string>
    <string name="Option_PharmEasy_url">https://www.pharmeasy.in/</string>
    <string name="Option_Netmeds_url">https://www.netmeds.com/</string>
    <string name="Option_Medlife_url">https://www.medlife.com/</string>
    <string name="Option_Practo_url">https://www.practo.com/</string>
    <string name="Option_Amazon_Pharmacy_url">https://www.amazon.in/pharmacy</string>
    <string name="Option_MedPlus_Mart_url">https://www.medplusmart.com/</string>
    <string name="Option_CVS_Pharmacy_url">https://www.cvs.com/</string>
    <string name="Option_Apollo_To_Name_A_Few_url">https://www.apollopharmacy.in/</string>
    <string name="Option_CVS_Pharmacy">Order medicine using CVS Pharmacy</string>
    <string name="Option_MedPlus_Mart">Order medicine using MedPlus Mart</string>
    <string name="welcome_Para">Experience the future of skincare at your fingertips. SkinSprite offers instant skin analysis, personalized insights, and connects you with top local dermatologists. Explore our advanced features for a seamless and personalized skin health journey. Welcome to SkinSprite – where health meets innovation.</string>
    <string name="gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="camera">Camera</string>
    <string name="upload">Upload</string>
    <!-- Strings used for fragments for navigation -->
    <string name="first_fragment_label">First Fragment</string>
    <string name="second_fragment_label">Second Fragment</string>
    <string name="next">Next</string>
    <string name="previous">Previous</string>

    <string name="eczema_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Eczema, also known as atopic dermatitis, is a common skin condition that affects millions of people worldwide. It is characterized by red, itchy, and inflamed patches of skin that can appear anywhere on the body. While it is most commonly seen in children, it can also occur in adults.

    The exact cause of eczema is not fully understood, but it is believed to be a combination of genetic and environmental factors. People with a family history of eczema, allergies, or asthma are more likely to develop the condition. Environmental triggers such as irritants, allergens, and stress can also play a role in flare-ups.

    The symptoms of eczema can vary from person to person, but the most common ones include dry, itchy, and scaly skin, red or inflamed patches, and small bumps that may ooze or crust over. These symptoms can be uncomfortable and even painful, and they may lead to disrupted sleep and decreased quality of life.

    The good news is that eczema can be managed with proper treatment. The first step is to consult a qualified healthcare professional for an accurate diagnosis. They will evaluate your symptoms and medical history to determine if you have eczema and rule out other skin conditions.
    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="acne_rosacea_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Acne and Rosacea are two common skin conditions that can affect people of all ages. While they may share some similar symptoms, they are caused by different underlying factors and require different treatment approaches.

    Acne is a skin condition that occurs when hair follicles become clogged with oil, dead skin cells, and bacteria. This can result in the formation of whiteheads, blackheads, and pimples on the face, chest, and back. Symptoms of acne may include redness, inflammation, and scarring.

    On the other hand, Rosacea is a chronic skin disorder that causes redness and visible blood vessels in the face. It may also cause bumps and pimples, as well as a burning or stinging sensation. Unlike acne, Rosacea typically affects adults over the age of 30 and is more common in fair-skinned individuals.

    The exact causes of acne and Rosacea are not fully understood, but there are certain factors that can contribute to their development. These include genetics, hormonal changes, and environmental triggers such as stress, diet, and skincare products.

    It is important to note that both acne and Rosacea can have a significant impact on a person's self-esteem and quality of life. As such, it is crucial to seek proper diagnosis and treatment from a qualified healthcare professional.
    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="actinic_keratosis_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Actinic keratosis, basal cell carcinoma, and other malignant lesions are all types of skin diseases that can potentially be serious and should be treated by a qualified healthcare professional. These conditions are caused by sun exposure and can often appear as scaly, rough patches on the skin that may be red, pink, or brown in color.

    The most common symptom of these conditions is the appearance of a new or changing lesion on the skin. These lesions may be flat or raised, and may also be itchy or painful. They can occur on any part of the body, but are most commonly found on areas that are regularly exposed to the sun, such as the face, scalp, neck, and hands.

    The main cause of actinic keratosis, basal cell carcinoma, and other malignant lesions is long-term exposure to the sun's ultraviolet (UV) rays. This can be from spending too much time outdoors without protection, or from using tanning beds. People with fair skin, light-colored hair, and blue, green, or gray eyes are at a higher risk for developing these conditions.

    It is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional if you suspect that you may have actinic keratosis, basal cell carcinoma, or any other type of malignant lesion.
    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="exanthems_drug_eruptions_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Exanthems and Drug Eruptions are skin conditions that can be caused by a variety of factors, including medications, infections, and allergic reactions. These conditions are characterized by a rash or skin irritation that can be red, itchy, and sometimes painful.

    Symptoms of Exanthems and Drug Eruptions may include a rash that appears suddenly, often on the face, neck, and chest. The rash may be raised, flat, or blistered, and can be accompanied by itching, burning, or swelling. In some cases, the rash may also be accompanied by other symptoms, such as fever, joint pain, or fatigue.

    The causes of Exanthems and Drug Eruptions can vary, but they are often triggered by an immune response to a medication or infection. Certain medications, such as antibiotics, anti-seizure drugs, and non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs, are known to cause these skin reactions. Viral infections, such as herpes or measles, can also lead to Exanthems and Drug Eruptions.

    It is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional if you experience symptoms of Exanthems and Drug Eruptions. A doctor can properly diagnose the cause of the rash and provide appropriate treatment. This may include stopping the medication that is causing the reaction.
    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="herpes_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Herpes is a common viral infection caused by the herpes simplex virus (HSV). There are two types of HSV, type 1 (HSV-1) and type 2 (HSV-2), and both can cause herpes. HSV-1 is typically associated with oral herpes, also known as cold sores, while HSV-2 is primarily responsible for genital herpes.

    Symptoms of herpes can vary depending on the location of the infection. Oral herpes typically presents as painful blisters or sores on the lips, mouth, or face. Genital herpes can cause similar blisters or sores on the genitals, buttocks, or anus. These blisters may break open and form ulcers, which can be painful and may take 2-4 weeks to heal. Other symptoms may include fever, headache, muscle aches, and swollen lymph nodes.

    Herpes is highly contagious and can be transmitted through direct contact with an infected person or through contact with their saliva, skin, or genital secretions. It can also be transmitted through sexual contact, including vaginal, anal, or oral sex. It is important to note that herpes can still be transmitted even when there are no visible symptoms present.

    While there is no cure for herpes, there are treatments available to help manage the symptoms and reduce the risk of transmission. These may include antiviral medications, which can help to reduce the severity and duration of outbreaks, as well as

    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="light_diseases_disorders_pigmentation_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Light diseases and disorders of pigmentation refer to a group of skin conditions that affect the color of the skin. These conditions can range from minor discolorations to more serious conditions that require medical attention.

    Symptoms of light diseases and disorders of pigmentation can vary depending on the specific condition, but some common signs include changes in skin color, such as darkening or lightening of the skin, patches of skin that appear lighter or darker than the surrounding skin, and skin that appears blotchy or discolored.

    The causes of these conditions can also vary, but some factors that may contribute to their development include genetics, sun exposure, hormonal changes, certain medications, and underlying medical conditions.

    It is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional for a proper diagnosis and treatment plan for any skin condition. They will be able to accurately diagnose the specific condition and provide appropriate treatment options.

    While there are various treatments available for light diseases and disorders of pigmentation, it is important to note that there is no guaranteed cure for these conditions. Treatment options may include topical creams, laser therapy, chemical peels, or oral medications, depending on the severity and type of condition.
    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="lupus_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Lupus, also known as systemic lupus erythematosus (SLE), is a chronic autoimmune disease that affects multiple organs and systems in the body. It is characterized by the body\'s immune system attacking its own tissues and organs, leading to inflammation and damage.

    The symptoms of lupus can vary greatly from person to person and can also change over time. Some common symptoms include joint pain and stiffness, skin rashes (particularly a butterfly-shaped rash on the face), fatigue, fever, hair loss, and sensitivity to sunlight. Other symptoms may include chest pain, shortness of breath, headaches, and memory loss.

    The exact cause of lupus is unknown, but it is believed to be a combination of genetic, environmental, and hormonal factors. Women are more likely to develop lupus than men, and it often develops between the ages of 15 and 44. Certain medications, infections, and exposure to sunlight or chemicals may also trigger lupus in some individuals.

    It is important to note that lupus is a complex and unpredictable disease, and there is currently no known cure. However, with proper management and treatment, most people with lupus can lead full and active lives. Treatment may include medications to control symptoms and prevent flares, as well as

    ]]>
</string>


    <string name="melanoma_skin_cancer_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Melanoma skin cancer, also known as malignant melanoma, is a type of cancer that affects the skin cells called melanocytes. Melanocytes are responsible for producing a pigment called melanin, which gives our skin its color.

    Symptoms of melanoma skin cancer may include changes in the appearance of moles, such as asymmetry, irregular borders, changes in color or size, and the presence of multiple colors within the same mole. Other symptoms may include the development of new moles, sores that do not heal, and changes in the texture of the skin.

    The exact cause of melanoma skin cancer is not fully understood, but it is believed to be a combination of genetic and environmental factors. People with fair skin, light-colored eyes, and a history of sunburns or excessive sun exposure are at a higher risk of developing melanoma. Other risk factors include a family history of melanoma, a weakened immune system, and a history of using tanning beds.

    It is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional if you notice any changes in your moles or skin. A healthcare professional will perform a thorough examination and may order a biopsy to determine if the mole is cancerous. Early detection and treatment of melanoma can greatly increase the chances of successful

    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="poison_ivy_contact_dermatitis_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Poison Ivy and other forms of contact dermatitis are skin conditions that can cause discomfort and irritation. These conditions occur when the skin comes into contact with a substance that triggers an allergic reaction or irritation.

    Symptoms of contact dermatitis can include redness, itching, and blisters. In the case of poison ivy, the skin may also develop a rash that can be accompanied by swelling and oozing blisters. These symptoms can appear within hours or days of coming into contact with the irritant.

    The most common cause of contact dermatitis is exposure to a specific substance, such as poison ivy, poison oak, or poison sumac. These plants contain a substance called urushiol, which can cause an allergic reaction in some people. Other common irritants include certain metals, chemicals, and cosmetics.

    It is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional if you suspect you have contact dermatitis. A doctor can properly diagnose the condition and provide appropriate treatment. This may include over-the-counter or prescription creams, ointments, or oral medications to help alleviate symptoms. In some cases, a doctor may also recommend avoiding the irritant in the future to prevent future outbreaks.

    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="psoriasis_lichen_planus_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Psoriasis, Lichen Planus, and related skin diseases are all conditions that affect the skin and can cause discomfort and irritation. While they may share some similarities, they each have their own unique characteristics and require different treatment approaches. It is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional for accurate diagnosis and treatment.

    Psoriasis is a chronic autoimmune disorder that causes the skin cells to multiply at an abnormally fast rate, resulting in thick, red, and scaly patches on the skin. These patches can appear anywhere on the body, but are most commonly found on the scalp, elbows, knees, and lower back. In addition to the physical symptoms, psoriasis can also cause itching, burning, and pain.

    Lichen Planus is also a chronic inflammatory skin condition that can affect the skin, hair, nails, and mucous membranes. It is characterized by itchy, flat-topped, and purplish bumps that can appear on the skin, especially on the wrists, ankles, and lower back. In some cases, Lichen Planus can also cause white patches in the mouth, which can be painful and make eating difficult.

    Both psoriasis and Lichen Planus can be triggered by a variety of factors, including stress, infections, and certain medications. However,
    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="seborrheic_keratoses_benign_tumors_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Overview of Seborrheic Keratoses and Other Benign Tumors:

    Seborrheic Keratoses and other benign tumors are skin growths that are non-cancerous and do not pose a serious health risk. They are common in adults and are usually found on areas of the skin that are exposed to the sun, such as the face, arms, and hands.

    Symptoms:

    The main symptom of Seborrheic Keratoses is the appearance of raised, waxy, and scaly growths on the skin. These growths can vary in color from light tan to dark brown and may have a warty or rough texture. They can range in size from a few millimeters to several centimeters and may appear alone or in groups.

    Other benign tumors, such as dermatofibromas, lipomas, and neurofibromas, may have similar symptoms of raised growths on the skin. However, they may have different characteristics, such as a soft or firm texture and different colors.

    Causes:

    The exact cause of Seborrheic Keratoses and other benign tumors is unknown. However, they are thought to be linked to genetics, sun exposure, and age.
    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="systemic_disease_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Systemic diseases, also known as systemic disorders or systemic illnesses, are conditions that affect the whole body rather than just one specific organ or area. These diseases can be caused by a variety of factors, including genetics, environmental triggers, and lifestyle choices.

    Symptoms of systemic diseases can vary greatly, depending on the specific condition and the individual. However, some common symptoms include fatigue, fever, weight loss, joint pain, and skin rashes. In some cases, systemic diseases may also affect the function of major organs, such as the heart, lungs, or kidneys.

    The causes of systemic diseases are not always clear, and many are still being studied by medical professionals. Some conditions are thought to be caused by an overactive immune system, while others may be linked to genetic mutations or environmental factors such as toxins or infections.

    It is important to note that systemic diseases can be difficult to diagnose, as their symptoms can mimic those of other conditions. Therefore, it is crucial to consult a qualified healthcare professional for an accurate diagnosis. They will be able to review your medical history, perform necessary tests, and provide a proper treatment plan.

    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="tinea_ringworm_fungal_infection_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Tinea, also known as ringworm, candidiasis, and other fungal infections are common skin conditions caused by various types of fungi. These infections can affect different parts of the body, including the scalp, feet, groin, and nails.

    Symptoms of tinea and other fungal infections may vary depending on the type and location of the infection. However, some common symptoms include red, itchy, and scaly skin, blisters, and in some cases, hair loss. In severe cases, the affected area may also become swollen, painful, and develop pus-filled bumps.

    The causes of these fungal infections can vary, but they are often spread through direct contact with an infected person or animal, or by coming into contact with contaminated objects or surfaces. People with weakened immune systems, such as those with HIV or diabetes, are at a higher risk of developing these infections.

    It is essential to consult a qualified healthcare professional for an accurate diagnosis and appropriate treatment. They may perform a physical examination and take a skin sample to identify the specific type of fungus causing the infection. Treatment options may include topical or oral antifungal medications, depending on the severity and location of the infection.

    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="urticaria_hives_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Urticaria, also known as hives, is a common skin condition that affects millions of people worldwide. It is characterized by raised, itchy, and often red welts on the skin that can vary in size and shape. These welts, also known as wheals, can appear on any part of the body and can come and go quickly, sometimes within a few hours.

    The exact cause of urticaria is not fully understood, but it is believed to be triggered by an allergic reaction or release of histamine in the body. This can be caused by a variety of factors, including certain foods, medications, insect bites, infections, and underlying health conditions.

    Symptoms of urticaria can vary from person to person, but the most common ones include raised red welts on the skin, intense itching, and a burning or stinging sensation. In some cases, hives may also be accompanied by swelling of the lips, tongue, or face, difficulty breathing, and dizziness.

    While urticaria can be uncomfortable and sometimes alarming, it is usually not a serious condition and can be treated with over-the-counter antihistamines. However, it is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional if you experience hives frequently or if they last

    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="vascular_tumors_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Vascular tumors are a type of abnormal growth that occurs in the blood vessels. They can develop anywhere in the body, but are most commonly found on the skin and in soft tissues. These tumors can be either benign (non-cancerous) or malignant (cancerous).

    The symptoms of vascular tumors can vary depending on the type and location of the tumor. Some common symptoms include a visible lump or bump on the skin, pain or tenderness in the affected area, and changes in skin color or texture.

    The exact cause of vascular tumors is not fully understood. However, research suggests that genetic factors and environmental triggers may play a role in their development. Some vascular tumors may also be linked to certain medical conditions, such as von Hippel-Lindau disease or Sturge-Weber syndrome.

    If you suspect that you may have a vascular tumor, it is important to consult a qualified healthcare professional for diagnosis and treatment. They will be able to properly assess your condition and recommend the most appropriate course of action. This may include further testing, such as imaging scans or a biopsy, and potentially surgery or other treatments.

    It is important to note that there is no guaranteed cure for vascular tumors. Treatment options will vary depending on the type and severity of the tumor, and

    ]]>
</string>

    <string name="warts_viral_infections_info">
    <![CDATA[
    Warts, Molluscum, and other viral infections are common skin conditions caused by various viruses. These infections can affect people of all ages and can be transmitted through direct contact with an infected person or object.

    Symptoms of these viral infections can vary depending on the type of virus and the area of the body affected. Some common symptoms include small, raised bumps on the skin, itching, and redness. In the case of warts, they can also have a rough or cauliflower-like appearance.

    The most common cause of these viral infections is the human papillomavirus (HPV) for warts, and the molluscum contagiosum virus (MCV) for molluscum. These viruses can enter the body through small cuts or breaks in the skin and can also be spread through direct contact with an infected person or object.

    It is essential to consult a qualified healthcare professional if you suspect you have a viral infection. While warts and molluscum may go away on their own over time, treatment options are available to help speed up the healing process and reduce the risk of transmission. These may include over-the-counter or prescription medications, cryotherapy, or other medical procedures.

    ]]>
</string>


</resources>